<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<trials>

<trial>
    <main>
        <trial_id>2019-001083-30-SE</trial_id>
        <utrn></utrn>
        <reg_name>EU Clinical Trials Register</reg_name>
        <date_registration>03/04/2019</date_registration>
        <primary_sponsor>Karolinska Institutet</primary_sponsor>
        <public_title>A clinical trial to evaluate the effect of the anti-viral drug Valganciclovir in brain tumor patients</public_title>
        <acronym></acronym>
        <scientific_title>A multicenter randomized double-blinded controlled 
phase 2 study evaluating the efficacy of valganciclovir as 
add-on therapy in glioblastoma patients 
</scientific_title>
        <scientific_acronym></scientific_acronym>
        <date_enrolment>02/06/2019</date_enrolment>
        <type_enrolment>Date trial authorised</type_enrolment>
        <target_size>220</target_size>
        <recruitment_status>Authorised-recruitment may be ongoing or finished</recruitment_status>
        <url>https://www.clinicaltrialsregister.eu/ctr-search/search?query=eudract_number:2019-001083-30</url>
        <study_type>Interventional clinical trial of medicinal product</study_type>
        <study_design>Controlled: yes
Randomised: yes
Open: no
Single blind: no
Double blind: yes
Parallel group: no
Cross over: no
Other: no
If controlled, specify comparator, Other Medicinial Product: no
Placebo: yes
Other: no
Number of treatment arms in the trial: 2
</study_design>
        <phase>Human pharmacology (Phase I): no
Therapeutic exploratory (Phase II): yes
Therapeutic confirmatory - (Phase III): no
Therapeutic use (Phase IV): no
</phase>
        <hc_freetext>Glioblastoma is an incurable brain tumor with very dismal prognosis. Substantial evidence demonstrates that cytomegalovirus (CMV) is present in 90-100% of malignant glioblastoma.We have observed that valganciclovir is well tolerated among glioblastoma patients receiving temozolomide and radiation therapy. We further observed that treatment with valganciclovir may enhance the survival chances for glioblastoma patients. We aim to assess the efficacy of Valganciclovir in glioblastoma patients.</hc_freetext>
        <i_freetext>
Product Name: valganciclovir
Pharmaceutical Form: Tablet
Pharmaceutical form of the placebo: Tablet
Route of administration of the placebo: Oral use

</i_freetext>
        <results_actual_enrolment></results_actual_enrolment>
        <results_date_completed></results_date_completed>
        <results_url_link></results_url_link>
        <results_summary>A multicenter randomized double-blinded controlled 
phase 2 study evaluating the efficacy of valganciclovir as 
add-on therapy in glioblastoma patients 
</results_summary>
        <results_date_posted></results_date_posted>
        <results_date_first_publication></results_date_first_publication>
        <results_baseline_char>No results available</results_baseline_char>
        <results_participant_flow>No results available</results_participant_flow>
        <results_adverse_events>No results available</results_adverse_events>
        <results_outcome_measures>No results available</results_outcome_measures>
        <results_url_protocol></results_url_protocol>
        <results_IPD_plan></results_IPD_plan>
        <results_IPD_description></results_IPD_description>
    </main>
    <contacts>
        <contact>
            <type>Public</type>
            <firstname>Konstantinos Kostulas@sll.se</firstname>
            <middlename></middlename>
            <lastname></lastname>
            <address>Karolinska Universitetssjukhuset Hotellet plan 4</address>
            <city>Solna</city>
            <country1>Sweden</country1>
            <zip>17176</zip>
            <telephone>+4672595 7237</telephone>
            <email>konstantinos.kostulas@sll.se</email>
            <affiliation>Karolinska University Hospital; SLL</affiliation>
        </contact>
        <contact>
            <type>Scientific</type>
            <firstname>Konstantinos Kostulas@sll.se</firstname>
            <middlename></middlename>
            <lastname></lastname>
            <address>Karolinska Universitetssjukhuset Hotellet plan 4</address>
            <city>Solna</city>
            <country1>Sweden</country1>
            <zip>17176</zip>
            <telephone>+4672595 7237</telephone>
            <email>konstantinos.kostulas@sll.se</email>
            <affiliation>Karolinska University Hospital; SLL</affiliation>
        </contact>
    </contacts>
    <countries>
        <country2>United States</country2>
        <country2>Israel</country2>
        <country2>Sweden</country2>
    </countries>
    <criteria>
        <inclusion_criteria>
1.	Patients aged 18 years or older
2.	Patients with newly diagnosed glioblastoma, IDH 1 wt, WHO grade IV
3.	Radical resection; no more than 1 cm3 remaining contrast enhancement tumor by MRI or CT, postoperatively.
4.	Concomitant treatment with temozolomide and radiation therapy
5.	MGMT promoter methylation status
6.	Patients with at least KPS 70 , ECOG/WHO 2
7.	Patients providing written informed consent
8.	Patients cooperative and able to complete all the assessment procedures.
9.	Patient agrees to utilize two reliable methods of contraception combined throughout the study period. 
10.	Females of childbearing age potential must have a negative pregnancy test at screening.
11.	Patients must be enrolled within 6 weeks after surgery

Are the trial subjects under 18? no
Number of subjects for this age range: 
F.1.2 Adults (18-64 years) yes
F.1.2.1 Number of subjects for this age range 150
F.1.3 Elderly (&gt;=65 years) yes
F.1.3.1 Number of subjects for this age range 70
</inclusion_criteria>
        <agemin></agemin>
        <agemax></agemax>
        <gender>
Female: yes
Male: yes
</gender>
        <exclusion_criteria>
1.	Patients allergic to, or who do not tolerate Valganciclovir, aciclovir or valaciclovir treatment
2.	Patients with decreased cognitive function (below 24 in MMSE test)
3.	Pregnant or lactating females
4.	Patients not signing informed consent
5.	Patient is simultaneously participating in another experimental drug therapy trial
6.	Neutrophil count &lt; 1500 cells/mm3l 
7.	Platelet count &lt; 150 000 cells/ mm3
8.	HGB &lt; 8g/dL
9.	Abnormal renal function (GFR &lt; 30)
10.	Secondary glioblastoma, or glioblastoma IDH1 mutated.
11.	Unfit for any other reason judged by investigator

</exclusion_criteria>
    </criteria>
    <health_condition_code>
        <hc_code>Therapeutic area: Diseases [C] - Cancer [C04]</hc_code>
    </health_condition_code>
    <health_condition_keyword>
        <hc_keyword></hc_keyword>
    </health_condition_keyword>
    <intervention_code>
        <i_code></i_code>
    </intervention_code>
    <intervention_keyword>
        <i_keyword></i_keyword>
    </intervention_keyword>
    <primary_outcome>
        <prim_outcome>Main Objective: To assess the efficacy of Valganciclovir in glioblastoma patients.</prim_outcome>
        <prim_outcome>Secondary Objective: Evaluate tumor volume, proportion of patients with stable / progressive disease, quality of life, safety aspects and subgroup analyzes regarding CMV status. </prim_outcome>
        <prim_outcome>Primary end point(s): Primary endpoint point: Median overall survival at 30 months follow up time.</prim_outcome>
        <prim_outcome>Timepoint(s) of evaluation of this end point: 30 months follow up time after inclusion.</prim_outcome>
    </primary_outcome>
    <secondary_outcome>
        <sec_outcome>Secondary end point(s): •	Proportion of patients alive at 12 and 24  months 
•	Overall progression free survival (RANO and NANO criteria)
•	Quality of life assessments (EORTC QoL  questionnaire at base line and every three months at routine checkups  (3, 6, 9, 12, 15 18, 21, 24 and 30 months)
•	Patient overall survival and median survival time (patients are followed until death). 
•	Proportion of patients with progressive disease at 24 months (RANO criteria). 
•	Proportion of patients with progressive disease at 24 months (Clinical and NANO criteria). 
•	Proportion of patients with stable disease at 12 and 24 months (RANO criteria).
•	Proportion of patients with recurrence at 12 and 24 months
•	Continuous proportion of progressive disease 
•	Continuous proportion of stable disease 
•	Continuous proportion of patients with treatment failure
•	Subgroup analyses will be performed on CMV positive patients. 
•	Safety assessements
</sec_outcome>
        <sec_outcome>Timepoint(s) of evaluation of this end point: Tumor volume/ disease status assessments at 12 and 24 months, Quality of life assessments at:3, 6, 9, 12, 15, 18, 21, 24 och 30 months. </sec_outcome>
    </secondary_outcome>
    <secondary_sponsor>
        <sponsor_name></sponsor_name>
    </secondary_sponsor>
    <secondary_ids>
        <secondary_id>
            <sec_id>VIGAS2</sec_id>
            <issuing_authority>Sponsor Protocol Code</issuing_authority>
        </secondary_id>
    </secondary_ids>
    <source_support>
        <source_name>Karolinska Instituet</source_name>
    </source_support>
    <ethics_reviews>
        <ethics_review>
            <status>Approved</status>
            <approval_date>23/04/2021</approval_date>
            <contact_name></contact_name>
            <contact_address></contact_address>
            <contact_phone></contact_phone>
            <contact_email></contact_email>
        </ethics_review>
    </ethics_reviews>
</trial>

<trial>
    <main>
        <trial_id>2021-004897-77-Outside-EU/EEA</trial_id>
        <utrn></utrn>
        <reg_name>EU Clinical Trials Register</reg_name>
        <date_registration>13/09/2021</date_registration>
        <primary_sponsor>Intas Pharmaceuticals Ltd. </primary_sponsor>
        <public_title>Comparative pharmacokinetics study (study to know the amount of study drug (cyclophosphamide) in your blood at specified time points – to understand “what body does to this study drug) of two products of cyclophosphamide powder for oral solution and Cyclophosphamide Tablets 50 mg in adult patients with breast cancer</public_title>
        <acronym></acronym>
        <scientific_title>A multicentric, open label, balanced, randomized, two-stage, two-treatment, two-period, two-sequence, crossover, multiple oral dose, comparative bioavailability study of cyclophosphamide powder for oral solution (Test drug from Intas pharmaceutical Ltd., India) with Cyclophosphamide Tablets 50 mg (Reference drug from Baxter) in adult patients with breast cancer.</scientific_title>
        <scientific_acronym></scientific_acronym>
        <date_enrolment></date_enrolment>
        <type_enrolment></type_enrolment>
        <target_size></target_size>
        <recruitment_status>NA</recruitment_status>
        <url>https://www.clinicaltrialsregister.eu/ctr-search/search?query=eudract_number:2021-004897-77</url>
        <study_type>Interventional clinical trial of medicinal product</study_type>
        <study_design>Controlled: yes
Randomised: yes
Open: yes
Single blind: no
Double blind: no
Parallel group: no
Cross over: yes
Other: no
If controlled, specify comparator, Other Medicinial Product: no
Placebo: no
Other: yes
Other specify the comparator: Cyclophosphamide Tablets 50 mg
Number of treatment arms in the trial: 2
</study_design>
        <phase>Human pharmacology (Phase I): yes
Therapeutic exploratory (Phase II): no
Therapeutic confirmatory - (Phase III): no
Therapeutic use (Phase IV): no
</phase>
        <hc_freetext>Adult female patients with breast cancer.</hc_freetext>
        <i_freetext>
Product Name: Cyclophosphamide powder for oral solution 600 mg / 20 mL
Pharmaceutical Form: Powder for oral solution
INN or Proposed INN: CYCLOPHOSPHAMIDE
CAS Number: 50-18-0
Concentration unit: mg/ml milligram(s)/millilitre
Concentration type: equal
Concentration number: 30-

Trade Name: Cyclophosphamide Tablets 50 mg
Product Name: Cyclophosphamide Tablets 50 mg
Pharmaceutical Form: Tablet
INN or Proposed INN: CYCLOPHOSPHAMIDE
CAS Number: 50-18-0
Concentration unit: mg milligram(s)
Concentration type: equal
Concentration number: 50-

</i_freetext>
        <results_actual_enrolment></results_actual_enrolment>
        <results_date_completed></results_date_completed>
        <results_url_link></results_url_link>
        <results_summary>A multicentric, open label, balanced, randomized, two-stage, two-treatment, two-period, two-sequence, crossover, multiple oral dose, comparative bioavailability study of cyclophosphamide powder for oral solution (Test drug from Intas pharmaceutical Ltd., India) with Cyclophosphamide Tablets 50 mg (Reference drug from Baxter) in adult patients with breast cancer.</results_summary>
        <results_date_posted></results_date_posted>
        <results_date_first_publication></results_date_first_publication>
        <results_baseline_char>No results available</results_baseline_char>
        <results_participant_flow>No results available</results_participant_flow>
        <results_adverse_events>No results available</results_adverse_events>
        <results_outcome_measures>No results available</results_outcome_measures>
        <results_url_protocol></results_url_protocol>
        <results_IPD_plan></results_IPD_plan>
        <results_IPD_description></results_IPD_description>
    </main>
    <contacts>
        <contact>
            <type>Public</type>
            <firstname>Mr. Kavan Pandya</firstname>
            <middlename></middlename>
            <lastname></lastname>
            <address>Corporate House, Nr. Sola Bridge, S. G. Highway, Thaltej</address>
            <city>Ahmedabad</city>
            <country1>India</country1>
            <zip>380054</zip>
            <telephone></telephone>
            <email>kavan_pandya@intaspharma.com</email>
            <affiliation>Intas Pharmaceuticals Ltd. </affiliation>
        </contact>
        <contact>
            <type>Scientific</type>
            <firstname>Mr. Kavan Pandya</firstname>
            <middlename></middlename>
            <lastname></lastname>
            <address>Corporate House, Nr. Sola Bridge, S. G. Highway, Thaltej</address>
            <city>Ahmedabad</city>
            <country1>India</country1>
            <zip>380054</zip>
            <telephone></telephone>
            <email>kavan_pandya@intaspharma.com</email>
            <affiliation>Intas Pharmaceuticals Ltd. </affiliation>
        </contact>
    </contacts>
    <countries>
        <country2>India</country2>
    </countries>
    <criteria>
        <inclusion_criteria>
1. Participant must sign an ICF indicating that she understands the purpose of, and procedures required for the study as described in this protocol and is willing to participate in the study.
2. Participant must be female of weight ≥40 kg, aged between 18 to 55 years of age inclusive, at the time of signing the informed consent.
3. Participants with documented medical history of histologically or cytologically confirmed breast cancer.
4. Participant must have of HER2 negative, ER/PR positive or negative breast cancer [as defined by American Society for Clinical Oncology (ASCO)- College of American Pathologists (CAP) guidelines] confirmed by local laboratory performed on primary tumor and/or metastatic lesion.
5. Patients who are
a. Neoadjuvant, adjuvant, recurrent, or metastatic setting
AND
b. To be initiated on cyclophosphamide 100 mg/m2 (rounded within 5% of the prescribed dose but always in multiples of 50 mg per day) daily for at least 14 days by oral route with established treatment regimen either as a monotherapy or as part of combination therapy as per independent clinical judgement of a treating physician based on standard medical care.
OR
Already receiving stable dose of cyclophosphamide 100 mg/m2 (rounded within 5% of the prescribed dose in multiples of 50 mg per day) daily for at least 14 days by oral route with established treatment regimen either as a monotherapy or as part of combination therapy as per independent clinical judgement of a treating physician based on standard medical care.
6. Documented disease progression (clinical or radiographic imaging) following most-recent anti-cancer systemic study intervention regimen before current cyclophosphamide therapy (not applicable for newly diagnosed patients/adjuvant patients).
7. An Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status (PS) 0 or 1 at screening and baseline visit.
8. Body mass index (BMI) within the range 18.5 – 30 kg/m2 (inclusive) at screening and baseline.
9. Life expectancy of ≥12 weeks at screening and baseline. Patients are required to be in stable health status between the two periods of the study.
10. Patient must have recovered from acute toxicity of radiotherapy or previous cycle of chemotherapy before baseline visit. Patients if have received radiotherapy (regardless of site &amp; dose), a gap of 28 days must be maintained between the last dose of radiotherapy and baseline visit.
11. Patient with adequate hematologic, liver and renal function at screening visit.
12. A female participant is eligible to participate if she is not pregnant or breastfeeding, and at least one of the following conditions applies:
•	Is not a woman of childbearing potential (WOCBP)
OR
•	Is a WOCBP and using a contraceptive method that is highly effective (with a failure rate of &lt;1% per year), with low user dependency when used consistently and correctly, as described in Appendix 10.4 during the intervention period and for at least 12 months after the last dose of study intervention and agrees not to donate eggs (ova, oocytes) for the purpose of reproduction during the study and for a period of at least 12 months. The investigator should evaluate the effectiveness of the contraceptive method in relationship to the first dose of study intervention.
•	A WOCBP must have a negative highly sensitive serum pregnancy test at screening; and urine pregnancy test before the first dose of study intervention at baseline visit.
•	If a urine test cannot be confirmed as negative (e.g., an ambiguous result), a serum pregnancy test is required. In such cases, the participant must be excluded from participation if the serum pregnancy result is positive.
•	Additional requirements for pregnancy testing during and after study intervention are located in Appendix 10.2.
•	The investigator is responsible for review of medical history, menstrual history, and recent sexual activity to decrease the risk for inclusion of a woman with an early undetected pregnancy.
13. Willing and able to adhere to the lifestyle restrictions specified in this protocol.

Are the trial subjects under 18? no
Number of subjects for this age range: 
F.1.2 Adults (18-64 years) yes
F.1.2.1 Number of subjects for this age range 24
F.1.3 Elderly (&gt;=65 years) no
F.1.3.1 Number of subjects for this age range 
</inclusion_criteria>
        <agemin></agemin>
        <agemax></agemax>
        <gender>
Female: yes
Male: no
</gender>
        <exclusion_criteria>
1.	History of clinically significant medical condition including but not limited to liver insufficiency; significant cardiac, vascular, pulmonary, gastrointestinal, endocrine, neurologic, hematologic, rheumatologic, psychiatric, or metabolic disturbances; any severe, acute, or chronic medical, psychiatric or social condition; or laboratory abnormality that as per Investigator's opinion may either (a) not be in the best interest of the participant, (b) interfere with the informed consent process and/or with compliance with the requirements of the trial, or (c) prevent, limit, or confound the protocol-specified assessments or (d) result in the variation of absorption or metabolism of drug, i.e., ulcerative colitis, or gastrointestinal disease.
2.	Known allergies, hypersensitivity, or intolerance to cyclophosphamide powder or tablet or its excipients 
3.	Contraindications to the use of cyclophosphamide per SmPC at screening and at baseline.
•	Participant with bladder/urinary toxicity of cyclophosphamide.
•	Participant with urinary outflow obstructions or acute urothelial toxicity from cytotoxic chemotherapy or radiation therapy.
•	Participant with bone marrow aplasia.
•	Participant with severe infection within 4 weeks prior to randomization,  bacteremia, or severe pneumonia OR Received oral or IV antibiotics within 2 weeks prior to Baseline visit. Patients receiving routine antibiotic prophylaxis are eligible.
4.	Had of major surgery, within 12 weeks before screening, or will not have fully recovered from surgery, or has surgery planned during the time the participant is expected to participate in the study or within 30 days after the last dose of study intervention administration.
5.	History of hepatitis B surface antigen or hepatitis C antibody positive, or other clinically active liver disease, or tests positive for HBsAg or anti-HCV at Screening Visit.
6.	History of human immunodeficiency virus antibody positive, or tests positive for HIV at Screening Visit.
7.	History of drug or alcohol abuse according to Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders criteria within 1 year before Screening or positive test result(s) for alcohol or drugs of abuse at Screening Visit.
8.	Lymphoma, leukemia, or any malignancy within the past 5 years except for malignancy under study, basal cell or squamous epithelial carcinomas of the skin that have been resected with no evidence of metastatic disease for 3 years; carcinoma in situ of the cervix; or malignancy, which is considered cured with minimal risk of recurrence
9.	Current unstable liver or biliary disease per investigator assessment defined by the presence of ascites, encephalopathy, coagulopathy, hypoalbuminemia, esophageal or gastric varices, persistent jaundice, or cirrhosis.
10.	QTc &gt;470 msec or QTc &gt;480 msec in participants with bundle branch block. The QTc is the QT interval corrected for heart rate according to Bazett’s formula. It is either machine-read or manually over-read.
11.	More than one prior line of chemotherapy for locally advanced or metastatic breast cancer. Radiation therapy or endocrine therapy for metastatic disease is permitted. 
12.	Patients unable to ingest oral medications.
13.	Known CNS disease, except for treated asymptomatic CNS metastases, provided all of the following criteria are met
•	Only supratentorial metastases allowed.
•	No evidence of interim progression or hemorrhage after completion of CNS-directed therapy.
•	No ongoing requirement for corticosteroids as therapy for CNS disease 
•	No stereotactic radiation within 14 days or whole-brain radiation within 28 days prior to randomization.
14.	Leptomeningeal disease.
15.	Spinal cord compression not definitively treated with surgery and/or radiation, or previously diagnosed and treated spinal cord compression without evidence that disease has been clinically stable for ≥4 weeks prior to Baseline.
16.	History of any of the following clinically significant cardiac conditions at screening and/or at Baseline:
•	Unstable angina
•	Myocardial infarction within the past 6 months of Baseline
•	Unstable arrhythmias
•	Clinically significant pericardial disease
•	Electrocardiographic evidence of acute ischemic or active conduction system abnormalities
•	Any other cardiac illness that could lead to a safety risk to the patient in case of enrolment in the study
•	Patients with a known left ventricular ejection fraction &lt;40% will be excluded.
•	Patients with known coronary artery disease, congestive heart failure not meeting the above criteria, or LVEF &lt;50% must be on a stable medical regimen that is optimized in the opinion of the treating physician, in consultation with a cardiologist if appropriate.
17.	Received an investigational intervention or used an invasive investigational medical device within 30 days or 5 half-lives prior to Baseline, whichever is longer, before the signing the consent or is currently enrolled in an investigational study.

</exclusion_criteria>
    </criteria>
    <health_condition_code>
        <hc_code>Therapeutic area: Diseases [C] - Cancer [C04]</hc_code>
    </health_condition_code>
    <health_condition_keyword>
        <hc_keyword>MedDRA version: 20.0
Level: PT
Classification code 10006187
Term: Breast cancer
System Organ Class: 10029104 - Neoplasms benign, malignant and unspecified (incl cysts and polyps)
</hc_keyword>
    </health_condition_keyword>
    <intervention_code>
        <i_code></i_code>
    </intervention_code>
    <intervention_keyword>
        <i_keyword></i_keyword>
    </intervention_keyword>
    <primary_outcome>
        <prim_outcome>Main Objective: To characterize the pharmacokinetic profile and to compare bioavailability of cyclophosphamide powder relative to cyclophosphamide tablet.</prim_outcome>
        <prim_outcome>Secondary Objective: - To evaluate taste/palatability of cyclophosphamide powder
- To compare the safety of cyclophosphamide powder relative to cyclophosphamide tablet.</prim_outcome>
        <prim_outcome>Primary end point(s): To characterize the pharmacokinetic profile and to compare bioavailability of cyclophosphamide powder relative to cyclophosphamide tablet.</prim_outcome>
        <prim_outcome>Timepoint(s) of evaluation of this end point: Following pharmacokinetic parameters will be evaluated:
- Primary Pharmacokinetic Parameters: Cmax,ss and AUC0-τ,ss
- Secondary Pharmacokinetic Parameters: Tmax,ss, Cav,ss, Cτ,ss, %Fluctuation and Cpd</prim_outcome>
    </primary_outcome>
    <secondary_outcome>
        <sec_outcome>Secondary end point(s): - To evaluate taste/palatability of cyclophosphamide powder
- To compare the safety of cyclophosphamide powder relative to cyclophosphamide tablet.</sec_outcome>
        <sec_outcome>Timepoint(s) of evaluation of this end point: - Test product palatability will be evaluated using palatability evaluation scale in terms of taste, flavor and mouth feel assessment.
- Frequency and/or incidence of significant clinical signs and symptoms, and laboratory abnormalities during treatment</sec_outcome>
    </secondary_outcome>
    <secondary_sponsor>
        <sponsor_name></sponsor_name>
    </secondary_sponsor>
    <secondary_ids>
        <secondary_id>
            <sec_id>0068-20</sec_id>
            <issuing_authority>Sponsor Protocol Code</issuing_authority>
        </secondary_id>
    </secondary_ids>
    <source_support>
        <source_name>Intas Pharmaceuticals Ltd.</source_name>
    </source_support>
    <ethics_reviews>
        <ethics_review>
            <status></status>
            <approval_date></approval_date>
            <contact_name></contact_name>
            <contact_address></contact_address>
            <contact_phone></contact_phone>
            <contact_email></contact_email>
        </ethics_review>
    </ethics_reviews>
</trial>

<trial>
    <main>
        <trial_id>2020-000301-87-DK</trial_id>
        <utrn></utrn>
        <reg_name>EU Clinical Trials Register</reg_name>
        <date_registration>11/08/2020</date_registration>
        <primary_sponsor>Repare Therapeutics</primary_sponsor>
        <public_title>A phase 1/2a trial to study how safe and tolerable RP-3500 is when administered along or in combination with talazoparib in patients with certain types of cancer</public_title>
        <acronym></acronym>
        <scientific_title>Phase 1/2a Study of the Safety, Pharmacokinetics, Pharmacodynamics and Preliminary Clinical Activity of RP-3500 Alone or in Combination with Talazoparib in Advanced Solid Tumors with ATR inhibitor Sensitizing Mutations (TRESR Study)</scientific_title>
        <scientific_acronym>TRESR Study</scientific_acronym>
        <date_enrolment>23/09/2020</date_enrolment>
        <type_enrolment>Date trial authorised</type_enrolment>
        <target_size>239</target_size>
        <recruitment_status>Authorised-recruitment may be ongoing or finished</recruitment_status>
        <url>https://www.clinicaltrialsregister.eu/ctr-search/search?query=eudract_number:2020-000301-87</url>
        <study_type>Interventional clinical trial of medicinal product</study_type>
        <study_design>Controlled: no
Randomised: no
Open: yes
Single blind: no
Double blind: no
Parallel group: no
Cross over: 
Other: no
If controlled, specify comparator, Other Medicinial Product: 
Placebo: no
Other: no
Number of treatment arms in the trial: 6
</study_design>
        <phase>Human pharmacology (Phase I): yes
Therapeutic exploratory (Phase II): yes
Therapeutic confirmatory - (Phase III): no
Therapeutic use (Phase IV): no
</phase>
        <hc_freetext>Advanced/recurrent solid tumors which have ATRi sensitizing biomarkers</hc_freetext>
        <i_freetext>
Product Name: RP-3500 5mg
Product Code: RP-3500
Pharmaceutical Form: Capsule, hard

Product Name: Talzenna
Product Code: MDV3800, BMN 673
Pharmaceutical Form: Capsule, hard
INN or Proposed INN: TALAZOPARIB
CAS Number: 1373431-65-2
Current Sponsor code: Talazoparib
Concentration unit: mg milligram(s)
Concentration type: equal
Concentration number: 0.25-

Product Name: RP-3500 40mg
Product Code: RP-3500
Pharmaceutical Form: Capsule, hard

</i_freetext>
        <results_actual_enrolment></results_actual_enrolment>
        <results_date_completed></results_date_completed>
        <results_url_link></results_url_link>
        <results_summary>Phase 1/2a Study of the Safety, Pharmacokinetics, Pharmacodynamics and Preliminary Clinical Activity of RP-3500 Alone or in Combination with Talazoparib in Advanced Solid Tumors with ATR inhibitor Sensitizing Mutations (TRESR Study)</results_summary>
        <results_date_posted></results_date_posted>
        <results_date_first_publication></results_date_first_publication>
        <results_baseline_char>No results available</results_baseline_char>
        <results_participant_flow>No results available</results_participant_flow>
        <results_adverse_events>No results available</results_adverse_events>
        <results_outcome_measures>No results available</results_outcome_measures>
        <results_url_protocol></results_url_protocol>
        <results_IPD_plan></results_IPD_plan>
        <results_IPD_description></results_IPD_description>
    </main>
    <contacts>
        <contact>
            <type>Public</type>
            <firstname>Clinical Operations</firstname>
            <middlename></middlename>
            <lastname></lastname>
            <address>1 Broadway, 15th Floor</address>
            <city>Cambridge, MA</city>
            <country1>United States</country1>
            <zip>02142</zip>
            <telephone></telephone>
            <email>clinical@reparerx.com</email>
            <affiliation>Repare Therapeutics</affiliation>
        </contact>
        <contact>
            <type>Scientific</type>
            <firstname>Clinical Operations</firstname>
            <middlename></middlename>
            <lastname></lastname>
            <address>1 Broadway, 15th Floor</address>
            <city>Cambridge, MA</city>
            <country1>United States</country1>
            <zip>02142</zip>
            <telephone></telephone>
            <email>clinical@reparerx.com</email>
            <affiliation>Repare Therapeutics</affiliation>
        </contact>
    </contacts>
    <countries>
        <country2>United States</country2>
        <country2>Canada</country2>
        <country2>Denmark</country2>
        <country2>United Kingdom</country2>
    </countries>
    <criteria>
        <inclusion_criteria>
1. Written informed consent, according to local guidelines, signed and dated by the patient or legal guardian prior to the performance of any study-specific procedures, sampling, or analyses.  
2. Male or female and ≥18 years-of-age at the time of signature of the ICF.
3. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) Performance Status score of 0 or 1.
4. Histologically confirmed solid tumors resistant or refractory to standard treatment and/or patients who are intolerant to standard therapy.
5. Measurable disease as per RECIST v1.1 
6. Existing biomarker profile (tumor tissue or plasma) reported from a local test obtained in a CAP/CLIA, ISO or equivalent lab per institutional guidelines:
a. Documented and confirmed by central review of local NGS reports by PODS, deleterious genomic alterations 
7. Provision of tumor tissue at Screening as per laboratory manual specifications. If archival tissue is available, the date of tumor tissue acquisition (e.g. biopsy or surgical resection) must be no older than 12 months from tissue procurement to enrollment. Enrolling centers must either provide 15 unstained slides, a tissue block with a minimum of 30% tumor content or obtain an adequate fresh biopsy sample prior to treatment. If adequate archived tumor tissue is not available and/or a fresh biopsy cannot be safely performed, the patient may still be eligible with prior sponsor approval.
8. Ability to comply with the protocol and study procedures detailed in the Schedule of Assessments.  
9. Ability to swallow and retain oral medications.
10. Acceptable organ function at Screening, as evidenced by the following laboratory data:
a. Serum creatinine ≤1.5 × upper limit of normal (ULN) or calculated creatinine clearance ≥60 mL/min using the Cockcroft-Gault equation or by 24-hour urine collection 
b. Total bilirubin ≤1.5 × ULN or &lt;3.0 × ULN if known Gilbert’s disease.
c. Serum albumin ≥2.5 g/dL
d. Aspartate aminotransferase (AST) and alanine aminotransferase (ALT) ≤2.5 × ULN unless liver metastases are present and thought to be a reason for AST/ALT elevation, in which case they must be ≤5 × ULN
11. Acceptable hematologic function at Screening
a. No red blood cell or platelet transfusions or growth factors within 7 days of the first dose of RP-3500
b. Hemoglobin ≥9.5 g/dL 
c. ANC ≥1700 cells/mm3
d. Platelet count ≥150,000 cells/mm3
12. Negative pregnancy test (serum or urine) for women of childbearing potential (WOCBP) at Screening and prior to first study drug. Non-WOCBP is defined as 1) adequate time of amenorrhea plus adequate follicle stimulating hormone (FSH) level or 2) surgically or anatomically infertile.
13. Resolution of all toxicities of prior therapy or surgical procedures to baseline or Grade 1 (except for neuropathy, hypothyroidism requiring medication and alopecia which must have resolved to Grade ≤2). 
14. Male patients with female partners of childbearing potential and WOCBP must follow a contraception method (oral contraceptives allowed) at least as conservative as Clinical Trial Facilitation Group (CTFG) recommendations during their participation in the study and for 4 months following last dose of study drug. Male patients must also refrain from donating sperm during their participation in the study and for 4 months following last dose of study drug.
15. Life expectancy ≥12 weeks after the start of the treatment according to the investigator’s judgment.




Are the trial subjects under 18? no
Number of subjects for this age range: 
F.1.2 Adults (18-64 years) yes
F.1.2.1 Number of subjects for this age range 202
F.1.3 Elderly (&gt;=65 years) yes
F.1.3.1 Number of subjects for this age range 37
</inclusion_criteria>
        <agemin></agemin>
        <agemax></agemax>
        <gender>
Female: yes
Male: yes
</gender>
        <exclusion_criteria>
1. Chemotherapy, small molecule anticancer or biologic anticancer therapy given within 14 days prior to first dose of study drug. For patients with breast or prostate cancer continuation of long-term luteinizing hormone-releasing hormone (LHRH) or previously prescribed Receptor activator of nuclear factor kappa-B ligand (RANKL) inhibitor or bisphosphonates is allowed. 
2. History or current condition (such as transfusion dependent  anemia or thrombocytopenia), therapy, or laboratory abnormality that might confound the study results, or interfere with the patient’s participation for the full duration of the study treatment.
3. Prior therapy with an ATR or DNA-dependent protein kinase (DNA-PK) inhibitor.
4. Known hypersensitivity to any of the ingredients of RP-3500. 
5. Life-threatening illness, medical condition, active uncontrolled infection, or organ system dysfunction (such as coagulopathy, encephalopathy or ascites requiring drainage within 4 weeks prior to enrollment) or other reasons which, in the investigator’s opinion, could compromise the patient’s safety, or interfere with or compromise the integrity of the study outcomes. 
6. Uncontrolled, symptomatic brain metastases. Patients with previously treated brain metastases may participate provided the metastases are stable (without evidence of progression by imaging for at least 4 weeks prior to the first dose of study drug and any neurologic symptoms are controlled and stable), have no evidence of new or enlarging brain metastases, and are clinically stable off steroids for at least 7 days prior to study drug.
7. Uncontrolled hypertension (systolic blood pressure [BP] ≥160 mmHg; diastolic BP ≥100 mmHg) despite adequate treatment prior to first dose of RP-3500.
8. Patients with active, uncontrolled bacterial, fungal, or viral infection, including hepatitis B virus (HBV), hepatitis C virus (HCV), known human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) or acquired immunodeficiency syndrome (AIDS) related illness.  In equivocal cases, patients whose viral load is negative, may be eligible.  HIV seropositive patients who are healthy and low risk for AIDS related outcomes could be considered eligible.  Eligibility criteria for HIV positive patients should be evaluated and discussed with sponsor’s Medical Monitor, and will be based on current and past CD4 and T-cell counts, history (if any) of AIDS-defining conditions (eg, opportunistic infections), and status of HIV treatment. 
9. Moderate or severe hepatic impairment (ie, Child-Pugh class B or C).
10. History or presence of an abnormal ECG that is clinically significant in the investigator’s opinion, including complete left bundle branch block, second- or third-degree heart block, or recent history of myocardial infarction that in the opinion of the investigator will pose an increased risk of rhythm abnormalities.
11. QT interval corrected using Fridericia’s formula (QTcF) &gt;470 msec demonstrated by at least 2 ECGs &gt;30 minutes apart.
12. History of ventricular dysrhythmias or risk factors for ventricular dysrhythmias such as structural heart disease (eg, severe left ventricular systolic dysfunction, left ventricular hypertrophy), coronary heart disease (symptomatic or with ischemia demonstrated by diagnostic testing), clinically significant electrolyte abnormalities (eg, hypokalemia, hypomagnesemia, hypocalcemia), or family history of sudden unexplained death or long QT syndrome
13. Current treatment with medications that are well-known to prolong the QT interval (Appendix 4) .
14. History of myelodysplastic syndrome (MDS) or acute myeloid leukemia (AML) diagnosis
15. Psychological, familial, sociological, or geographical conditions that do not permit compliance with the protocol and/or follow-up procedures outlined in the protocol.
16. Patients who are receiving strong CYP3A inhibitors or inducers, P-glycoprotein (P-gP) inhibitors and/or breast cancer resistant protein (BCRP) inhibitors within 14 days prior to first dose of study drug

Additional Exclusion Criteria for Module 3:
17. Known hypersensitivity to any of the ingredients of talazoparib.
18. For patients entering into Module 3b, the following additional exclusion criteria apply:
  a. Rapid disease progression or threat to vital organs or critical anatomical sites (eg, CNS metastasis, respiratory failure due to tumor compression, spinal cord compression) requiring urgent alternative medical intervention
  b. Significant, unacceptable or irreversible toxicities related to the study treatment
  c. Other treatment discontinuation criteria are met
</exclusion_criteria>
    </criteria>
    <health_condition_code>
        <hc_code>Therapeutic area: Diseases [C] - Cancer [C04]</hc_code>
    </health_condition_code>
    <health_condition_keyword>
        <hc_keyword>MedDRA version: 21.1
Level: LLT
Classification code 10065252
Term: Solid tumor
System Organ Class: 100000004864
</hc_keyword>
    </health_condition_keyword>
    <intervention_code>
        <i_code></i_code>
    </intervention_code>
    <intervention_keyword>
        <i_keyword></i_keyword>
    </intervention_keyword>
    <primary_outcome>
        <prim_outcome>Main Objective: Module 1:
• To assess the safety and tolerability of RP-3500 in patients with eligible advanced solid tumors
• To define the maximum tolerated dose (MTD) of RP-3500 monotherapy, and determine a recommended phase 2 dose (RP2D) and schedule
Module 2:
• To Assess anti-tumor activity of RP-3500 when administered to eligible patients at the RP2D and schedule in selected genetic backgrounds
Module 3:
• To assess the safety and tolerability of RP-3500 and talazoparib combination in eligible patients with advanced solid tumors
• To define the MTD of RP-3500 and talazoparib combination and determine RP2D and schedule</prim_outcome>
        <prim_outcome>Secondary Objective: Module 1:
• Assess preliminary anti-tumor activity with RP-3500
• Characterize the PK profile of RP-3500
• Assess PK parameters of RP-3500 monotherapy in fasted and fed states
• Assess the relationship between PD biomarkers and PK of RP-3500 in a subset of patents to aid in schedule decisions and assess correlation with clinical outcomes
Module 2:
• Assess anti-tumor activity of RP-3500 in subsets of tumors tested in ARM 1
• Establish the preferred assay methods for defining how to select patients for ATRi sensitizing biomarkers for future studies
• Further characterize the PK profile of RP-3500
Module 3:
• Assess preliminary anti-tumor activity of RP-3500 and talazoparib combination in eligible patients
• Assess any PK interaction of RP-3500 and talazoparib combination
• Determine the PK/PD relationships of RP-3500 and talazoparib combination to confirm dose/schedule
• Determine activity of RP-3500 and talazoparib combination in patients who progressed after RP-3500 alone</prim_outcome>
        <prim_outcome>Primary end point(s): Safety:
• Dose-limiting toxicities (DLTs)
• Incidence of Treatment-emergent adverse event (TEAEs), treatment related TEAE, TEAEs leading to death, SAE,  treatment related  serious adverse event (SAE), TEAE leading to study drug discontinuation, TEAE leading to dose modifications and TEAE leading to study discontinuation summarized by system organ class (SOC) and MedDRA preferred term.
• Changes in clinical laboratory parameters (hematology, chemistry, urinalysis), Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events (CTCAE) graded laboratory toxicities, vital signs, Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status, ECG parameters, Physical examinations (PEs) and usage of concomitant medications
• 4β-hydroxycholesterol, a biomarker of CYP3A induction, will be evaluated at the RP2D

Efficacy:
• Objective response rate (ORR): confirmed best overall response of complete response (CR) or partial response (PR), based on investigator’s assessment using RECIST v1.1 
• Duration of response (DOR), based on investigator’s assessment using RECIST v1.1 
• Clinical benefit rate (CR + PR + stable disease [SD] ≥4 months), based on investigator’s assessment using RECIST v1.1 
• Progression-free survival time (PFS) and rate of PFS at 6 months, based on investigator’s assessment using RECIST v1.1 
• Rate of overall survival (OS) at 12 months</prim_outcome>
        <prim_outcome>Timepoint(s) of evaluation of this end point: Safety: 
Throughout the Trial

Efficacy: 
Confirmed overall response rate (ORR), duration of response (DOR), clinical benefit rate (CR + PR + stable disease [SD] ≥4 months), progression free survival (PFS) at 6 months, and overall survival (OS) at 12 months in the analysis population</prim_outcome>
    </primary_outcome>
    <secondary_outcome>
        <sec_outcome>Secondary end point(s): Pharmacokinetics:
Blood samples will be drawn to determine RP-3500 and talazoparib PK parameters. Blood samples will be collected at the timepoints outlined in each module. Blood samples for the analysis of 4β-hydroxycholesterol, a biomarker of CYP3A induction, will be collected in patients in Module 1c at or near the RP2D (n = 10).

Biomarkers:
Pre- and on-treatment tumor biopsy samples will be collected to confirm target engagement at each dose/schedule and RP2D through measuring biomarkers such as pKAP1 and p-gammaH2Ax in pre- and on-treatment samples. Changes in the tumor-immune microenvironment also will be measured. Blood samples will be collected for ctDNA genomic analyses at timepoints outlined in each module. Baseline genomic profiles will be correlated with response to RP-3500 (or RP-3500 in combination with talazoparib).
</sec_outcome>
        <sec_outcome>Timepoint(s) of evaluation of this end point: PK and biomarker analysis timepoints vary by module. </sec_outcome>
    </secondary_outcome>
    <secondary_sponsor>
        <sponsor_name></sponsor_name>
    </secondary_sponsor>
    <secondary_ids>
        <secondary_id>
            <sec_id>RP-3500-01</sec_id>
            <issuing_authority>Sponsor Protocol Code</issuing_authority>
        </secondary_id>
        <secondary_id>
            <sec_id>NCT04497116</sec_id>
            <issuing_authority>US NCT Number</issuing_authority>
        </secondary_id>
        <secondary_id>
            <sec_id>2020-000301-87-GB</sec_id>
            <issuing_authority>EU CTR Parent ID</issuing_authority>
        </secondary_id>
    </secondary_ids>
    <source_support>
        <source_name>Repare Therapeutics</source_name>
    </source_support>
    <ethics_reviews>
        <ethics_review>
            <status>Approved</status>
            <approval_date>20/08/2020</approval_date>
            <contact_name></contact_name>
            <contact_address></contact_address>
            <contact_phone></contact_phone>
            <contact_email></contact_email>
        </ethics_review>
    </ethics_reviews>
</trial>

</trials>